Guide to the Harriet Wasserman Literary Agency Records, 1940s-2000 and undated (bulk 1978-1995) RL.00509
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings Series, A-Z, 1941-1995
  - Writings (Books) Subseries, A-Z, 1944-1994 and undated
    - Williams, Jay, 17
      - The Time of the Kraken
        - hardback: British (Box WB-24)
      - Tomorrow's Fire
        - paperback: British (Box WB-24)
      - The Water of Life (Box WB-24)
    - Winegardner, Mark
      - The Veracruz Blues
        - uncorrected bound proof (acknowledgement) (Box WB-24)
    - Winslow, Joan, 2
      - Romance is a Riot, 2
        - hardback: American (Box WB-24)
        - uncorrected bound proof (Box WB-24)
    - Witty, Helen, 2
      - Better Than Store-Bought: A Cookbook
        - hardback: American (inscribed) (Box WB-24)
      - Mrs. Witty's Home-Style Menu Cookbook
        - paperback: American (Box WB-24)
    - Young, Miriam, 4
      - No Place For Mitty (Box WB-24)
      - Truth and Consequences (Box WB-24)
      - A Witch's Garden, 2
        - hardback: American, large print (Box WB-24)
- Miscellaneous Series, A-Z, 1953-1995
  This series consists of various secondary materials about the authors. Clippings of reviews make up the bulk of this material, but the series also includes many advertisements, publishers' catalogs, and other publicity as well as a number of photographs and audiovisual items. Audiovisual materials are master copies only; use copies will be made on request. In the current accession there is only one subseries, which is open.
  - Amoss, Berthe, 1982 (Box MO-1)
  - Bausch, Richard, 1980-1987; 1992-1994 (Box MO-1)
  - Bellow, Saul, Interviews, 1953-1963 (Box MO-1)
  - Bellow, Saul, 1964 (Box MO-1)
  - Bellow, Saul, Interviews, 1964-1965 (Box MO-1)
  - Bellow, Saul, 1968 (Box MO-1)
  - Bellow, Saul, Interviews, 1971-1973 (Box MO-1)
  - Bellow, Saul, 1973-1974 (Box MO-1)
  - Bellow, Saul, Interviews, 1974 (Box MO-1)
  - Bellow, Saul, 1975, 2 folders (Box MO-1)
  - Bellow, Saul, Interviews, 1975 (Box MO-1)
  - Bellow, Saul, 1976, 2 folders (Box MO-1)
  - Bellow, Saul, Interviews, 1976 (Box MO-1)
  - Bellow, Saul, 1977 (Box MO-1)
  - Bellow, Saul, Interviews, 1977 (Box MO-1)
  - Bellow, Saul, 1978-1980, 3 folders (Box MO-1)
  - Bellow, Saul, Interviews, 1980 (Box MO-1)
  - Bellow, Saul, 1981, 2 folders (Box MO-1)
  - Bellow, Saul, Interviews, 1981 (Box MO-1)
  - Bellow, Saul, 1982, 4 folders (Box MO-1)
  - Bellow, Saul, Interviews, 1982 (Box MO-1)
  - Bellow, Saul, 1983 (Box MO-1)
  - Bellow, Saul, Interviews, 1983 (Box MO-1)
  - Bellow, Saul, 1984, 4 folders (Box MO-1)
  - Bellow, Saul, Interviews, 1984 (Box MO-1)
  - Bellow, Saul, 1985 (Box MO-2)
  - Bellow, Saul, Lois Phillips Files, 1985, 2 folders (Box MO-2)
    For further information about Phillips files see Correspondence (Open) Subseries, Bellow, 1985 and that subseries' note
  - Bellow, Saul, 1986-1992, 5 folders (Box MO-2)
  - Bellow, Saul, Interviews, 1990-1991 (Box MO-2)
  - Bellow, Saul, 1993-1994, 2 folders (Box MO-2)
  - Bellow, Saul, Interviews, 1995 (Box MO-2)
  - Bellow, Saul. (Box MO-2)
    See also Oversize Material (Boxes and Cabinets)
  - Biddle, Wayne, undated (Box MO-2)
  - Biddle, Wayne. (Box MO-2)
    See Oversize Material (Boxes)
  - Bloom, Allan, 1987-1988, 3 folders (Box MO-2)
  - Bolton, Ruthie, Gal: A True Life, 1994, 2 folders (Box MO-2)
  - Buechner, Frederick, 1980-1990 and undated, 2 folders (Box MO-2)
  - Clark, Eleanor, 1964 and undated (Box MO-2)
  - Delving, Michael, undated (Box MO-2)
  - Goldstein, Rebecca, undated (Box MO-2)
  - Hijuelos, Oscar, 1990-1991 and undated, 2 folders (Box MO-2)
  - Humphreys, Josephine, 1989 and undated (Box MO-2)
  - Merchant-Ivory, 1993 (Box MO-2)
  - Jhabvala, C.S.H., 1986-1992 (Box MO-2)
  - Jhabvala, Ruth Prawer, 1976-1990 (Box MO-2)
  - Kennan, George Frost, 1982-1994, 2 folders (Box MO-3)
  - King, Francis, 1988 (Box MO-3)
  - Koperwas, Sam. undated (Box MO-3)
  - Kreyling, Michael, 1979-1989 (Box MO-3)
  - Lansbury, Coral, 1986-1989 (Box MO-3)
  - Lee, Laurel, 1977 (Box MO-3)
  - Markus, Julia, 1981-1995 and undated (Box MO-3)
  - McDermott, Alice, 1981-1992 and undated, 3 folders (Box MO-3)
  - McMahon, Thomas, 1981, 1991 (Box MO-3)
  - Mooney, Ted, 1979, 1981 (Box MO-3)
  - Myers, Walter Dean, 1982-1983 and undated (Box MO-3)
  - Naumoff, Lawrence, 1988-1990 (Box MO-3)
  - Onassis, Jacqueline, 1994 (Box MO-3)
  - Philidor Trio, 1967, 1970 (Box MO-3)
  - Price, Reynolds, 1976-1990 and undated (Box MO-3)
  - Price, Reynolds. (Box MO-3)
  - Walter, Eugene, undated (Box MO-3)
  - Wasserman, Harriet, 1975, 1983-1994
    - Inscriptions, Acknowledgments, and Dedications to Harriet Wasserman (Box MO-3)
  - Wilcox, James, undated (Box MO-3)
  - Witty, Helen, 1986 (Box MO-3)
  - Audiovisual materials (Box MO-4)
    - Bausch, Richard
      - The Last Good Time, directed by Bob Balaban, 1994, VHS videocassette (Box MO-4)
    - Bellow, Saul
      - Chicago Public Library speech, 1972 October, audiocassette (Box MO-4)
      - Chicago's Authors Celebrate Chicago, including Looking for Mr. Green read by Bill Kurtis, undated, audiocassettes (Box MO-4)
      - Interview for Swiss television, 1987 April, VHS videocassette (Box MO-4)
      - Interview on and reading from The Dean's December, directed by Dennis Marks, 1982, VHS videocassette (Box MO-4)
      - Interview with Charlie Rose, CBS Nightwatch, 1987 August 21, VHS videocassette (Box MO-4)
      - Jefferson Lectures, Parts I and II, undated (Box MO-4)
      - Lecture by Bellow, 1986 December 4, audiocassette (Box MO-4)
      - MacNeil/Lehrer Newshour, 1987 June 22, VHS videocassette (Box MO-4)
      - Scatola Aperta, undated, 2 U-matic videocassettes (Box MO-4)
    - Hijuelos, Oscar
      - Mr. Ives' Christmas, excerpt in Readings and Conversations, promotional reader from HarperCollins, 1995 May (Box MO-4)
      - 14th Annual Hispanic Heritage Awards, undated (Box MO-4)
      - CityArts: Tales from the Book Trade, 1998 February (Box MO-4)
    - Kennan, George
      - Theatre X - Scratch Tape, Acts I and II, WMVS Television, undated (Box MO-4)
        (stage presentation based on Kennan's memoirs)
    - McDermott, Alice
      - Interview with McDermott and reading from Charming Billy (Box MO-4)
    - McCully, Emily
      - Caldecott Medal acceptance speech for Mirette on the High Wire 1993 June, audiocassette (Box MO-4)
    - Price, Reynolds
      - Clear Pictures, directed by Charles Guggenheim, 1995, VHS videocassette (Box MO-4)
      - A New Stretch of the Woods, read by Dick Harrington on The Sound of Writing, Program 27, hosted by Alan Cheuse, undated, audiocassette (Box MO-4)
- Oversize Materials, 1940-1995 and undated
  Arranged in subseries with the same names and restrictions as the related subseries in the main body of the collection.
  - Writings (Restricted) Subseries, A-Z, 1940s-1995 and undated (Box OM1)
    - Myers, Walter Dean.
      - Songhai! outline and time line (undated) RESTRICTED (Box OM1)
  - Writings (Open) Subseries, A-Z, 1948-1995 and undated
    - Bellow, Saul
      - Herzog Visits Chicago (print; 1964 August 8-15) (Box OM1)
  - Miscellaneous (Open) Subseries, A-Z, 1953-1995 and undatedA Whole New Life
    - Bellow, Saul.
      - Caricature of Bellow (Ayerson, 1984) (Box OM1)
      - Cover drawing for A Theft (by C.S.H. Jhabvala; undated) (Box OM1)
      - Humboldt's Gift poster (undated) (Box OM1)
      - Matted cover for It All Adds Up (undated) (Box OM1)
      - Matted cover for Something to Remember Me By (undated) (Box OM1)
      - Photograph of Bellow with Eudora Welty, Kurt (Box OM1)
      - Vonnegut, Norman Mailer (Jill Krementz, 1985 September) (Box OM1)
      - Publisher's flyer including Humboldt's Gift (1975 November 21) (Box OM1)
      - Mr. Sammler's Planet rejected cover (undated) (Box OM1)
      - More Die of Heartbreak ad mock-up and covers, matted (undated) (Box OM1)
    - Biddle, Wayne
      - Weapons in Space series reprinted from New York Times (not by Biddle; 1985) (Box OM1)
    - Hijuelos, Oscar
      - The Mambo Kings Play Songs of Love, matted poster of cover, undated (Box OM1)
    - McMahon, Thomas
      - Loving Little Egypt, poster for stage adaptation, 1991 (Box OM1)
    - Price, Reynolds
      - Cover for paperback edition of Mustian (Box OM1)
      - Photograph. Cover and title mock-up for Kate Vaiden (undated) (Box OM1)
  - Miscellaneous (Open) Subseries, 1953-1995 and undated
    - Bellow, Saul (Box Oversize 31)
      - Humboldt's Gift poster (undated) (Box Oversize 31)
      - More Die of Heartbreak book display, undated (Box Oversize 31)
    - Goldstein, Rebecca
      - The Mind-Body Problem poster, undated (Box Oversize 31)
    - Hijuelos, Oscar
      - Our House in the Last World, two posters, undated (Box Oversize 31)
    - Jhabvala, Ruth Prawer
      - Three Continents, matted poster, undated (Box Oversize 31)
    - Price Reynolds
      - Private Contentment playbill (1985 March) (Box Oversize 31)
- Accession (1999-0275)
  RESTRICTED: Viewing and copying the unpublished material of living authors is closed except by written permission. Copying published material is restricted and users must sign a release form before making copies. Contact Research Services for more information.
  - Client Files, 1975-1998 and undated
    Includes correspondence and other materials arranged alphabetically (with exceptions) by author/client. Some are then further arranged by dates, titles or projects.
    Attention: correspondence needs item-level processing before use. Restrictions on access to financial materials requires separation of these items from correspondence.
    Attention: Viewing and copying the unpublished material of living authors is closed except by written permission. Copying published material is restricted and users must sign a release form before making copies. Contact Research Services for more information.
    - Aa-Cl (Box 1)
      Files for the following clients: Chester Aaron, Berthe Amoss, John Auerbach, Richard Bach, Andrea Barnet, Walter Berns, Phyllis Birngaum, Allan Bloom, Martin Booth, Eleanor Bron, Wesley Brown, Mary Cable, Sara Cameron, Alan Cheuse, Eleanor Clark, Anastasia Cleaver
    - Cl-La (Box 2)
      Files for the following clients: Anastasia Cleaver, Kiana Davenport, Lydia Davis, Tom De Haven, Daniel De Souza, Marguerite Dorian, Joyce Engelson, Michael Evelyn, Wendy Ewald, William Fairchild, T. Gertler, GOSH, Carole Glickfeld, Rebecca Goldstein, Sheila Green, Jon Hassler, Erica Heller, Howard Jacobson, Jill Jones, Francis King, Norman Kotker, Karla Kuskin, Coral Lansbury (Lansbury pre-1990 file listed on the agency's original boxlist, not found during preliminary processing)
      CLOSED: Materials related to T. Gertler are closed to use until 2051.
    - Mc-Wa (Box 3)
      Files for the following clients: Tom McDonough, Rick Marshell, Silvia Sutton, Meredith Tax, Jean Thompson, Michael Underwood, James Wilcox, Eugene Walter, Ted Mooney, Joe Murray, Walter Dean Myers, Barbara Neil, Sigrid Nunez, Jane M. Orient (M. D.), Peter Parker, Stephen Pearl, Carol Ra, Ellen Raskin, Tor Seidler, William Jay Smith
  - Manuscripts, 1974-1998 and undated
    Filed under client name and title, then further arranged by dates of drafts and revisions and/or physical description of the texts. Client names are not in alphabetical order. See inventory file for a complete list of titles.
    - Oscar Hijuelos (Box 4)
    - Oscar Hijuelos, Frederick Buechner, Mark Smith, Wesley Brown, and Sam Koperwas (Box 5)
    - Wayne Biddle, Mark Winegardner, Rebecca Goldstein, Ted Mooney, and Tom McDonough (Box 6)
    - Bob Balaban, Sigrid Nunez, Sandra Ford, Jane Orient, John Bonner, and Julia Markus (Box 7)
    - Julia Markus, William S. Peterson and Julia Markus, Stuart Brent, Gordon Lish, Mark Girshin, Eugene Walter, Kiana Davenport, Oscar Hijuelos, Phyllis Birnbaum, Joan Winslow, Wayne Biddle, Wesley Brown, Marsha Dubrow, Mary Cable, and Berthe Amoss (Box 8)
    - Richard Bausch, Sigrid Nunez, Dr. Thomasina Blissard, Henry H. Bloomstein, and Ruth Prawer Jhabvala (Box 9)
    - Alice McDermott and The National Book Awards 49th Ceremony Program (Box 10)
    - Reynolds Price (Box 11)
    - Eileen Michaels, Sheila Greenwald, Sam Koperwas, Richard Bausch, Wesley Brown, Chester Aaron, Charles Bell, Joseph Alsop, and Kiana Davenport (Box 12)
    - John Auerbach, Frederick Buechner, Mark Winegardner, George F. Kennan, Tom McDonough, Daniel Voll, Daniel Walter Dean Myers, Richard Bausch, Reynolds Price, Natasha Peters, Anastasia Cleaver, Sheila Greenwald, and Wesley Brown (Box 13)
    - Olivia Coolidge, Martha Bayles, Adele Aron Schwarz, Literary Laurels: A Reader's Guide to Award-inning Fiction (HWLA clients up to 1995), Walter Isaacson and Evan Thomas, Robert Lasson and Sidney Shupak, Ellen Liman and Carol Panter, and Mirette on the High Wire. Acceptance Speeches, (cassette of speeches accepting awards: Caldecott medal, Emily Arnold McCully) (Box 14)
  - Saul Bellow Files, 1978-1994 and undated
    Includes correspondence, clippings, reviews, manuscripts, proofs, contracts and legal papers, printed materials, and miscellaneous materials.
    - Files and Reviews (1990-1994) (Box 14)
    - Cont. Files and Reviews (1990-1994) (Box 15)
    - Files (1982, 1984, 1987-1989) (Box 15)
    - Cont. Files (1982, 1984, 1987-1989) (Box 16)
    - Sotheby's auction (material held together in a shopping bag) (Box 16)
    - It All Adds Up, various editions and related materials (Box 17)
    - All Marbles Still Accounted For (Box 17)
    - A Case Of Love (Box 17)
    - More Die of Heartbreak, (fragment 2 pp.) (Box 17)
    - Unpublished short story (Box 17)
    - Him with his Foot in his Mouth and other Stories (Box 17)
    - Something to Remember Me By
      - French translation by Pierre Grandjouan (Box 17)
      - Sections and proofs (Box 17)
    - The Bellarosa Connection (Box 17)
    - The Bellarosa Connection, Feb.-Mar. 1989 (Box 18)
    - Contracts, magazines, miscellaneous papers (Box 18)
    - Press release materials for new publications (Box 18)
    - Plagiarized Herzog ( The Artist by Norman Garbo, NY: Norton, 1978) Partially annotated (Box 18)
    - Correspondence, miscellaneous materials, and clippings (Box 18)
    - Typescript of 4 colloquia at Syracuse University (Fall 1980), typescript sent Nov. 1981 (Box 18)
    - Correspondence about and copies of The Critical Response to Saul Bellow (Box 18)
    - Clippings, reviews, correspondence about permissions to reprint, translations, access to Bellow's papers (Box 18)
    - Copies of articles, interviews, speeches (Box 18)
    - Correspondence, contracts, copyright assignments, permissions to reprint, contracts for film rights and stage productions, 6 folders (Box 19)
  - Books
    Includes published materials of clients. See inventory file for a complete list of titles.
    - Richard Bausch, Ted Mooney, George F. Kennan, Allan Bloom, Cabbage and Bones. Anthology of Irish American Women's Fiction, Ruth Prawer Jhabvala, and Reynolds Price (Box 19)
    - Alice McDermott, Emily Arnold McCully, Mark Winegardner, Sheila Greenwald, Wayne Biddle, Julia Markus, Fredrick Buechner, Silvia Sutton, Sigrid Nunez, and Sharon Flake (Box 20)
    - Fredrica Wagman, Josephine Humphreys, Eileen Michaels, Sandra Lee Gould, Eleanor Clark, and Oscar Hijuelos (Box 21)
  - Handsome Is ...: Memoir by Harriet Wasserman
    - Ms. versions, proofs review article from Publisher's Weekly, 1977 Apr. 28 (Box 21)
    - Ms. versions, proofs, typescripts (Box 22)
  - Oversize Materials
    - Misc. oversize materials (Box 23)
    - More Die of Heartbreak, book display (Oversize-folder OC:I:11)
- Accessions 2001-0050 and 2001-0115
  Accession 2001-0115 in its entirety is interfiled in Box 8.
  Attention: Accession needs further processing before use. Sleeve photographs and negatives in boxes 3, 4, 5, and 8. Make use copy of audio cassette tape in box 4. Contact Technical Services.
  - Manuscripts by clients (Box 1)
    - Richard Bausch, "Valor" (Box 1)
    - Jay Williams
      - Stage Left (Box 1)
      - "Philbert the Fearful" (Box 1)
      - "The Roman Moon Mystery" (Box 1)
      - "The Stolen Oracle" (Box 1)
      - other manuscripts, 1 folder (Box 1)
    - Suzi-Lori Parks, "Gal" (screenplay) (Box 1)
    - Laurel Lee, manuscripts, 4 folders (Box 1)
    - Karla Kuskin, "Jane Anne Jane Spoon" (artwork) (Box 1)
    - Elinore Clark, "Out There" (Box 1)
    - Perrin Ireland, "Ana Imagined" versions, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Frederick Buechner, "Fact and Fiction" (Box 1)
      [in legal folder]
    - John Tyler Bonner
      - Memoirs for Family and Friends (inscribed galley) (Box 1)
      - The Life Cycle: From Slime Molds to Me, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Martha Moody/ Martha Jacobs (Box 2)
      - Big Future (working title for Best Friends), 2 folders (Box 2)
      - The Pornographer's Daughter (working title for Best Friends) (Box 2)
    - Eugene Walter, books (Box 2)
    - Caroline Winthrop, Icons, 2 copies (Box 2)
    - Eugene Walter, inscribed copy of "Singarie-Songarie" (Box 2)
    - Folder of Eugene Walter material (Box 2)
      Including the books The Likes of Which, The Untidy Pilgrim, and information about his poetry
    - Los Premios Pulitzer de Novela (book) (Box 2)
    - Paul Lussier, "Mr. Ives' Christmas" (screenplay) (Box 3)
    - A Field Guide to Germs black-and-white photographs and transparency (Box 3)
    - Reynolds Price, "Homeless. Home" (Box 3)
    - Sharon Flake
      - "A Freak Like Me" (Box 3)
      - "The Luckiest Sister" (Box 3)
      - "Girls Inc." (Box 3)
    - Reynolds Price
      - "A Perfect Friend", 4 folders (Box 3)
      - "Feasting the Heart" (Box 3)
      - "Three Gospels" (Box 3)
    - Josephine Humphreys
      - Rich in Love (Box 3)
      - Dreams of Sleep (Box 3)
      - The Fireman's Fair (Box 3)
      - Nowhere Else on Earth (galley copy) (Box 3)
    - Life magazine, Oct. 1986 (contains article on Saul Bellow) (Box 3)
  - Josephine Humphreys, Nowhere Else on Earth
    - galleys April 2000 (Box 3)
    - Nowhere Else on Earth (formerly titled The Queen of Scuffletown) drafts, 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Revised chapter 12 (Box 3)
    - Revised proofs (Box 4)
    - File with related maps and photos (Box 4)
  - Wasserman personal file with notes, clippings on Saul Bellow and Wasserman's book on Bellow (Box 4)
  - Magazines related to Bellow materials (Box 4)
  - Bette Howland, W-3 (with review by Saul Bellow) (Box 4)
  - Saul Bellow, Drumlin Woodchuck (Box 4)
  - Granta literary magazine with Saul Bellow, "Memoirs of a Bootlegger's Son" (Box 4)
  - Tillie Olsen, Yonnendio From the Thirties (Box 4)
  - Audiotape, Lenny Lopate interview for Handsome Is (Box 4)
  - Handsome Is correspondence (Box 4)
  - Handsome Is review (Box 4)
  - Harriet Wasserman, Handsome Is
    - Bound galley (Box 4)
    - Publishing materials (Box 4)
    - Photos (black and white, and copies) (Box 4)
    - Unbound galleys (Box 4)
    - Copyedited manuscript (Box 4)
    - Full manuscript (Box 4)
    - Chronology and proposals, 1 of 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Chronology and proposals, 2 of 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Clippings and correspondence, 2 folders (Box 5)
      (Contains 2 black and white photos)
  - George Dawson and Richard Glaubman, Life is So Good
    - Folder on Christopher Awards (Box 5)
    - Bound galley (Box 5)
    - Unedited/incomplete manuscript (Box 5)
    - Loose pages (Box 5)
    - Manuscript (Box 5)
    - Revised pages, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Richard Glaubman/ George Dawson, Life is So Good pages, 6 folders (Box 5)
  - Julia Markus, Across an Untried Sea
    - publication celebration invite (Box 5)
    - unbound galley (Box 5)
    - sample illustrations (Box 5)
    - full set of photos (photocopied) (Box 5)
    - note from author (Box 6)
    - manuscript copy (Box 6)
    - drafts with notes, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - draft up to p. 224, some notes (Box 6)
    - draft material, 6 folders (Box 6)
    - draft (Box 6)
    - set of illustrations (Box 6)
    - proposal submitted for contract (Box 6)
  - George F. Kennan, An American Kennan Family
    - book (Box 6)
    - f and g's (Box 6)
    - illustrations (photocopy) (Box 6)
    - edited material, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - several different versions of chapters 2 and 3 (Box 6)
    - proofs (Box 6)
    - article form, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - draft material, 3 folders (Box 6)
    - proofs with notes and correspondence (Box 7)
    - drafts (2) (Box 7)
    - copyedited manuscript (Box 7)
    - draft, 3 folders (Box 7)
    - maps and GFK's grandparents' marriage license (Box 7)
      [removed to oversize folder]
  - Carole L. Glickfeld, Swimming Toward the Ocean
    - First version, Under the Boardwalk (Box 7)
    - Several versions of last 100 pages (Box 7)
    - Manuscript (Box 7)
    - Proofs (Box 7)
  - Mark Winegardner, Crooked River Burning
    - Manuscript (Box 7)
    - Proposal (Box 8)
    - Bound galley (Box 8)
  - Harriet Wasserman, personal letters, photos, notes (Box 8)
    (contains 4 color, 1 black and white photo)
  - Michael Stewart, Belle (Box 8)
  - Saul Bellow photos and papers (Box 8)
    (contains 8 black and white photos)
  - University of Chicago Special Collections guide to Saul Bellow papers (Box 8)
  - Saul Bellow lectures 1988 - Arrangements (Box 8)
  - Correspondence with and about Diane Vreuls, 1974-1981 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence with and about Sandra Gould Ford, 1996-1997, 1993-1995, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Sandra Gould Ford, Faraday's Popcorn Factory reviews (Box 8)
  - Correspondence with and about Charles McPhee, 1991 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence with and about Mark Smith, 1983-1987 (Box 8)
  - 1999 International IMPAC Dublin Literary Award ( Alice McDermott, nominee) (Box 8)
  - Le Monde, 8 Sept. 1995 (includes article about Saul Bellow) (Box 8)
  - Correspondence with and about Saul Bellow (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous Oversize Material (Box Oversize 19)
  - Accession 2001-0115 (Box Oversize 19)
    Primarily correspondence between Wasserman and Shelley Gruskin. Also includes playbills and copy of In Dreams Begin Reponsibilities, by Delmore Schwartz.
- Accession 2003-0051
  [Accession is restricted. Patrons must obtain permission of donor before use.]
  - Drafts of various authors (Box 1)
    - Exhibitions (Box 1)
    - Hort Wrexler (Box 1)
    - Thomas McMahon (Box 1)
    - C.H.S. Jhabvala (Box 1)
    - Menaham Mier (Box 1)
    - Emily Jane Goodman (Box 1)
  - Drafts of various authors (Box 2)
    - Phyllis Birnbaum (Box 2)
    - Alice McDermott (Box 2)
    - Sheila Greenwald (Box 2)
    - Mark Winegardner (Box 2)
  - Drafts of various authors (Box 3)
    - Richard Bausch (Box 3)
    - Merchant Ivory (Box 3)
  - Drafts of various authors (Box 4)
    - Merchant Ivory (Box 4)
    - Thomas McMahon (Box 4)
    - Martha Moody (Box 4)
    - Richard Bausch (Box 4)
  - Drafts of various authors (Box 5)
    - Richard Bausch (Box 5)
  - Drafts of various authors (Box 6)
    - Richard Bausch (Box 6)
    - William Alfred (Box 6)
    - Alice McDermott (Box 6)
  - Drafts of various authors (Box 7)
    - Alice McDermott (Box 7)
    - Mark Winegardner (Box 7)
    - Frederick Buechner (Box 7)
    - Julia Markus (Box 7)
    - Laurel Lee (Box 7)
    - George Dawson and Richard Glaubman (Box 7)
  - Drafts of various authors (Box 8)
    - George Dawson and Richard Glaubman (Box 8)
    - Oscar Hijuelos (Box 8)
  - Drafts Oscar Hijuelos (Box 9)
    Contains pieces such A Simple Habana Melody, His Return to the City of Music and The Mambo Kings Play Songs of Love.
  - Drafts and works by various authors (Box 10)
    - Julia Markus (Box 10)
    - Merchant Ivory (Box 10)
    - George F. Kennan (Box 10)
    - Wesley Brown (Box 10)
    - Fernando Krahn (Box 10)
    - Launa Ochs (Box 10)
  - Drafts and works by various authors (Box 11)
    - Alice McDermott (Box 11)
    - E.M. Broner (Box 11)
    - Thomas McMahon (Box 11)